## ZETIAN YANG

No.19 XinJieKouWai Street, Beijing, China, 100875 +86 18001072860 · zetian.yang@gmail.com · Mind on Mind

#### **EDUCATION**

2012-present Beijing Normal University

M.S. in Cognitive Neuroscience (expected 2015) Advisor: Jia Liu & Zonglei Zhen

State Key Laboratory of Cognitive Neuroscience and Learning

2008-2012 Beihang University (former Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics)

B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology Major GPA: 3.79/4; Overall GPA: 3.66/4

#### RESEARCH SUMMARY

I use fMRI and behavioral tests to study the neural basis of object recognition and categorization, with a special interest in faces. In first part of my work, I studied the characteristics and individual differences of face-selective regions, by creating a probabilistic atlas for them. Based on that, my following research focuses on the relationships between different neural measures – category selectivity, pattern dissimilarity, representational geometry – of these regions, and how these neural measures relate to behavioral abilities.

## RESEARCH PROJECTS

Details about each project can be found by clicking on its title.

#### 2012-2014 Probabilistic Atlas of Six Face-selective Regions

Based on a large fMRI dataset and an efficient region labeling software (FreeROI) we developed, we delineated six face-selective regions on the ventral pathway of 202 subjects. A probabilistic atlas was created for the six regions, and different aspects of these regions were further characterized to quantify individual differences and hemisphere asymmetries.

Roles

- » Statistical processing of the fMRI dataset by FSL and scripts
- » One of the two core developers of FreeROI
- » Delineation of about 1000 subject-specific regions
- » Atlas construction and most further analysis
- » Part of manuscript preparation.

#### 2013-2014

# Differential Roles of Category Selectivity and Multivariate Pattern in Facial Expression and Identity Recognition

Using subject-specific ROI analysis and face-related behavioral tests, we found a double dissociation between univariate and multivariate neural measures: face selectivity in pSTS predicted facial expression recognition, but not facial identity recognition, while pattern dissimilarity in the same region predicted facial identity recognition, but not expression recognition.

Roles

- » Project designer
- » Data miner
- » Manuscript preparation

#### 2014-present

Interplay of Category Selectivity, Within-category Representation of Similarity, and Behavior Using representational similarity analysis (RSA), we are investigating the relationships between representational geometry, category selectivity, and behavior.

Roles

- » Project designer
- » Data miner

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Manuscripts

- Zhen Z\*, Yang Z\*, Huang L, Kong X, Wang X, Dang X, Huang Y, Song Y, Liu J. (*under review, Cerebral Cortex*), Quantifying Interindividual Variability and Asymmetry of Face-selective Regions: A Probabilistic Functional Atlas. \*co-first author
- Yang Z, Zhen Z, Song Y, Liu J. (*draft under revision*), Category Selectivity and Pattern Dissimilarity in pSTS Differentially Predict Facial Expression and Identity Recognition Abilities.

#### **Iournal Articles**

Huang L, Song Y, Li J, Zhen Z, Yang Z, Liu J. 2014. Individual Differences in Cortical Face Selectivity Predict Behavioral Performance in Face Recognition. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience. 8:483. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2014.00483

#### **Conference Presentations**

• Huang L, **Yang Z**, Zhou G, Liu Z, Dang X, Kong X, Wang X, Zhen Z, Liu J. 2014. FreeROI: A Software for Fast ROI Labeling and Visualization. *The 17th National Academic Congress of Psychology*, Beijing, China.

### Software Copyright

• CHN 00238594 - A Software for Brain Region Segmentation and Atlas Construction. Owner: Beijing Normal University; Main Developers: Huang L, **Yang Z** 

#### OTHER EXPERIENCE

2013-present	Auto-labeling of Fu	ınctional Regions	by SVM and	l Random Forests
--------------	---------------------	-------------------	------------	------------------

Project member participating for system and feature design

2012-present Center for Brain Imaging, Beijing Normal University

MRI scanning operator

2012 Machine Learning Class Accomplished on Coursera

#### **SKILLS**

fMRI Abundant experience with fMRI analysis software (FSL, FreeSurfer, etc.) in both GUI and script

usages; Proficient in common fMRI data analysis methods: ROI analysis, multivariate pattern analysis (MVPA), representational similarity analysis (RSA), and searchlight; Resting-state and VBM

analysis.

Programming Python; Matlab; C

Linux Arch, CentOS, Ubuntu, Fedora, etc.

Computer cluster construction and administration.

Standard TOEFL: 106 (R29, L27, S23, W27) Tests GRE: 333 (V165, Q168)+3.5 (AW)

Others Strong interests and good foundations in mathematical statistics and machine learning.

#### **HONORS & AWARDS**

2013	Excellent Academic Achievement (2nd-prize), BNU
2012	Excellent First-year Graduate Student, BNU
2012	Excellent in Student Research Training Program (SRTP), Beihang
2010	Samsung Scholarship, Beihang